Colten Cross

www.cwcross.com colten@cwcross.com | (762) 207-0132

SUMMARY

Software Developer with experience in front end and back end web development and cloud services. Supported both Cartoon Network and CNN Newsource websites, writing services used by thousands of users per day. Used to working in a close team and agile environment.

EDUCATION

GEORGIA STATE UNIVERSITY

May 2017 | Atlanta, GA BS IN PHYSICS COMP SCI CONCENTRATION Cum. GPA: 3.47 / 4.0

LINKS

Github:// ColCross LinkedIn:// ColtenCross

CERTIFICATIONS

COMPTIA SECURITY+

SECURITY CLEARANCE

DoD Secret

COURSEWORK

Software Engineering
Web Development
Data Structures
System-Level Programming
Math Models of Comp Sci

SOCIETIES

2016 - Sigma Pi Sigma (Physics Honor Society)

2014 - National Society of Collegiate Scholars

2012 - National Honor Society

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES / FRAMEWORKS

NodeJS • JS • HTML/CSS • Git • SQL • ReactJS • Java

CLOUD SERVICES

AWS - S3. SNS. Lambda

OPERATING SYSTEMS

OSX • Windows

WORK EXPERIENCE

CNN - TURNER | ADVANCED SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan 2018 - Present | Atlanta, GA

- Supporting the CNN Newsource Website and Video Affiliate Network (VAN).
- Writing Node applications for deployment through AWS Lambda functions.
- Implementing features for a React Redux environment.
- Writing API routes and PostgreSQL queries.

CARTOON NETWORK - TURNER | WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017 | Atlanta, GA

- Utilized JavaScript and jQuery to convert Cartoon Network website login and registration functionality to a new internal system and API.
- Collaborated with designers to implement new front-end redesign for registration, login and profile pages using HTML5/CSS3.
- Performed dev ops tasks such as updating misc pages, forms, and adding games.
- Used Git to maintain source control and merge code into staging and production environments.
- Employed full Agile methodologies through daily scrums and the JIRA ticketing system.
- Interacted with Cartoon Network Amazon S3 buckets to retrieve and store relevant files.

PROJECTS

DOG'S OUT OF THE BAG | HTTPS://GIT.IO/VF3WX

Oct 2017 - Present | Atlanta, GA

A small, unfinished blog template I am building in order to learn PHP and Symfony which power the Drupal framework being implemented by Cartoon Network. The site implements the full MVC paradigm and pulls and stores blog posts from a MySQL database. Current functionality includes adding, editing, and deleting posts.

MUON TELESCOPE | HTTPS://GIT.IO/VF3CE

Jan 2017 - April 2017 | Atlanta, GA

Assisted in designing and implementing a modular website for displaying data from Georgia State University's cosmic ray detector network. Utilized JavaScript and the Polymer framework to implement front-end web design, and a RESTful API amd MySQL for back-end database querying and management.